Furth, Josef Herbert; Papers ger036
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Correspondence, 1937-1981; 2; 208 folders
  - Polak, Jacques J., 1946; 1967 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 145)
  - Polk, Judd (Council on Foreign Relations, Inc), 1953 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 146)
  - Pollack, Gerald A., 1963 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 147)
  - Poullier, Jean-Pierre, 1962-1963 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 148)
  - Prochow, Herbert V., 1957-1961 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 149)
  - R, S - miscellaneous, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 150)
  - Rainoni, A., 1967 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 151)
  - Reierson, Roy L., 1959-1960 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 152)
  - Reinstein, Jacques J. (Foreign Service Institute), 1965-1966 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 153)
  - Reynolds, Stephen, 1978 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 154)
  - Richter, J. H. (Hans), 1960-1969 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 155)
  - Robertson, James Louis, 1958-1972 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 156)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1969 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 157)
  - Röpke, Wilhelm, 1949-1957 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 158)
  - Roosa, Robert V., 1956-1967 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 159)
  - Roper, Don E., 1972 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 160)
  - Ruff, Gunther, 1966-1968 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 161)
  - Salant, Walter S., 1958-1966 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 162)
  - Salin, Edgar, 1960-1969 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 163)
  - Schmidt, Wilson, 1961; 1972 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 164)
  - Schmitz, Wolfgang, 1968-1970 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 165)
  - Schmölders, G., 1962-1963 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 166)
  - Schueller, George H., 1969 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 167)
  - Schumpeter, Joseph A., 1947; Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 168)
  - Solmen, Egon, 1958-1960 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 169)
  - Solomon, Frederic, 1976 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 170)
  - Solomon, Robert, 1953-1967 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 171)
  - Sprott, John T., 1968-1969 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 172)
  - Staehle, Hans, 1952 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 173)
  - Stolper, Gustav, 1942 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 174)
  - Sturc, Ernest, 1948-1953 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 175)
  - Szymczak, Matt S., 1954-1966 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 176)
  - T, U, V -- miscellaneous, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 177)
  - Thomas, Woodlief (Woody), 1949 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 178)
  - Thorne, Wendell E., 1947-1959 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 179)
  - Thorp, Willard L., 1954; 1958 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 180)
  - Tintner, Gerhard, 1956-1974 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 181)
  - Triffin, Robert, 1959; 1966 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 182)
  - Trued, Merlyn N., 1965 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 183)
  - Vaznaugh, F. S., 1969 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 184)
  - Vernon, Raymond, 1969 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 185)
  - Vocke, Wilhelm, 1950 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 186)
  - Voegelin, Eric, 1980 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 187)
  - Volcker, Paul A., 1969 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 188)
  - von der Lippe, Viktor Freiherr, 1961 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 189)
  - W-Z -- miscellaneous, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 190)
  - Wagner, Helmut R., 1975-1976 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 191)
  - Wallich, Henry C., 1951-1969 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 192)
  - Weisskopf, Walter A., 1981 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 193)
  - Weissman, R. L., 1963-1965 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 194)
  - Westebbe, Richard M., 1961-1962 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 195)
  - Whittlesey, C. Raymond, 1945-1965 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 196)
  - Widenman, Hans, 1969 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 197)
  - Willner, Robert T., 1971 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 198)
  - Wilson, Charles R., 1949 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 199)
  - Wood, Ralph, 1958 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 200)
  - Young, Ralph A., 1961-1968 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 201)
  - Zaglits, Oscar, 1959 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 202)
  - Zassenhaus, Herbert K., 1949-1961 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 203)
  - Zimmer-Lehmann, Georg, 1955-1967 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 204)
  - Zolotas, Xenophon, 1954; 1967 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 205)
  - Health insurance, 1955-1963 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 206)
  - Publishers, general correspondence, Undated (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 207)
  - Miscellaneous personal correspondence, 1952-1964 (Box 2 (2-Correspondence), Folder 208)
- Foreign Dollar Balances, 1967-1973; 3; 23 folders
  This series contains typescripts of the study Foreign Dollar Balances and the International Role of the Dollar, co-authored with Raymond F. Mikesell (1972). Included are typescripts of chapters, as well as a bound copy of the preliminary draft dated Dec. 1972. Also included in the series is extensive correspondence with co-author Raymond F. Mikesell and with Hal B. Lary of the National Bureau of Economic Research, Inc., under whose auspices the study was published, as well as criticisms of the study by other economists.
  Typescripts arranged chronologically, followed by correspondence arranged alphabetically.
  - "Foreign Holdings of Liquid Dollar Assets", 1967 January 17 (Box 3 (3-Foreign Dollar Balances), Folder 1)
  - Foreign Dollar Balances: "Chapter II", 1967 April (Box 3 (3-Foreign Dollar Balances), Folder 2)
  - Foreign Dollar Balances: "Introduction"; "Summary and Conclusions", 1967 September (Box 3 (3-Foreign Dollar Balances), Folder 3)
  - Foreign Dollar Balances: "Chapter III", 1967 September 29 (Box 3 (3-Foreign Dollar Balances), Folder 4)
  - Foreign Dollar Balances: "Note on Concept and Measurement of 'Additionality' of Foreign Euro-Dollar Balances", 1967 October (Box 3 (3-Foreign Dollar Balances), Folder 5)
  - Foreign Dollar Balances: "Revised draft", 1968 March (Box 3 (3-Foreign Dollar Balances), Folder 6)
  - Foreign Dollar Balances: "Statistical Tables", Undated (Box 3 (3-Foreign Dollar Balances), Folder 7)
  - "Foreign Dollar Balances and the U.S. Balance of Payments (A Prospectus of a Study by J. Herbert Furth and Raymond F. Mikesell)", 1969 September 15 (Box 3 (3-Foreign Dollar Balances), Folder 8)
  - "Introduction to Seminar Discussion of Foreign Dollar Balances", 1970 August 12 (Box 3 (3-Foreign Dollar Balances), Folder 9)
  - Mikesell, Raymond F. and J. Herbert Furth.Foreign Dollar Balances and the International Role of the Dollar, 1972 December (Box 3 (3-Foreign Dollar Balances), Folder 10)
    Bound typescript with the note "Preliminary and Confidential".
  - Correspondence and criticisms re, 3.11
    - Lary, Hal B. (National Bureau of Economic Research, Inc), 1948-1958; 1966-1968 (Box 3 (3-Foreign Dollar Balances), Folder 11)
    - Lary, Hal B., 1969-1974 (Box 3 (3-Foreign Dollar Balances), Folder 12)
    - Mikesell, Raymond F., 1968-1969 (Box 3 (3-Foreign Dollar Balances), Folder 13)
    - Mikesell, Raymond F., 1970 (Box 3 (3-Foreign Dollar Balances), Folder 14)
    - Mikesell, Raymond F., 1971 (Box 3 (3-Foreign Dollar Balances), Folder 15)
    - Mikesell, Raymond F., 1972-1973 (Box 3 (3-Foreign Dollar Balances), Folder 16)
    - Cagan, P. Criticism of Mikesell/Furth, 1972 (Box 3 (3-Foreign Dollar Balances), Folder 17)
    - Eldridge, Douglas H. Criticism of Mikesell/Furth, 1973 (Box 3 (3-Foreign Dollar Balances), Folder 18)
    - Kindleberger, C.P. Criticism of Mikesell/Furth, 1968 (Box 3 (3-Foreign Dollar Balances), Folder 19)
    - Klopstock, Fred H. Criticism of Mikesell/Furth, 1967 (Box 3 (3-Foreign Dollar Balances), Folder 20)
    - Lederer, Walther. Criticism of Mikesell/Furth, 1972 (Box 3 (3-Foreign Dollar Balances), Folder 21)
    - Sammons, Robert L. Criticism of Mikesell/Furth, 1972 (Box 3 (3-Foreign Dollar Balances), Folder 22)
    - Stern, Carl H. Criticism of Mikesell/Furth, 1972 (Box 3 (3-Foreign Dollar Balances), Folder 23)
- Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth for the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve Board, 1944-1966; 4; 75 folders
  This series contains copies, both in typescript and final form, of Furth's studies conducted for the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve Board and spans nearly the entire period of Furth's employment by the Federal Reserve Board.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - "Problems of Austrian Finance", 1944 October (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 24)
  - "The Greek Hyper-Inflation", 1944 October (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 25)
  - "Stabilization of the Greek Currency", 1944 December 5 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 26)
  - "Financial Policy in Liberated Austria", 1945 January (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 27)
  - "Money and Banking in Liberated Belgium", 1945 April (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 28)
  - "Economic Relations Between the United States and Near Eastern Countries", 1945 April 30 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 29)
  - "Financial Problems of Liberated Europe", 1945 May (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 30)
  - "Yugoslavia. Economic and Financial Developments", 1946 June (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 31)
  - "German Assets in Austria", 1946 October 21 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 32)
  - "The Foreign Trade of the American and British Zones of Occupation", 1947 July 1 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 33)
  - "Austria's Coal Imports -- A Case Study in Postwar International Economic Arrangements", 1947 August 26 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 34)
  - "U.S. Economic Policy in Germany", 1947 July 29 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 35)
  - "Germany and the Plan for European Economic Development", 1947 November 4 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 36)
  - "'Controlled Inflation' in Austria", 1947 October 7 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 37)
  - "Currency Reform in Austria", 1947 December 2 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 38)
  - "Greek Foreign Trade and Exchange Policies", 1947 December 16 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 39)
  - "Free Market versus Parity Rates", 1948 February 24 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 40)
  - "Austrian Finance", 1948 June (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 41)
  - "Currency Reform in Germany", 1948 July 13 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 42)
  - "Some Thoughts on Import Restrictions", 1948 November 16 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 43)
  - "Domestic Effects of Currency Reform in Western Germany", 1949 March 8 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 44)
  - "Currency Conversion and Foreign Trade of Western Germany", 1949 March 29 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 45)
  - "Foreign Exchange Problems in Austria", 1949 September 13 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 46)
  - "Central Banking Policies and the Disequilibrium in the German Economy"/ "Revaluation of the Ruble", 1950 March 28 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 47)
  - "Economic Survey of Europe -- Some Fragmentary Comments", 1950 July 18 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 48)
  - "A Controlled Criticism of the German Experiment", 1951 February 13 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 49)
  - "Equilibrium and disequilibrium in the German Economy", 1951 April 10 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 50)
  - "A New Theory of Economic Development", 1951 June 5 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 51)
  - "Austria -- Prosperity and Inflation", 1952 June 3 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 52)
  - "Recent Economic Developments in Western Europe", 1952 November 18 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 53)
  - "Monetary Stability and Currency Convertibility", 1952 December 6 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 54)
  - "Economic Survey of Postwar Europe", 1953 June 30 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 55)
  - "The International Financial Position of the United Kingdom -- Problems and Prospects", 1953 July 7 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 56)
  - "Currency Convertibility and Monetary Policy", 1953 December 17 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 57)
  - "The International Financial Position of the United Kingdom, 1953 and 1925", 1954 February 2 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 58)
  - "The World Economy in 1954. The U.S. Economy in the World Economy", 1954 February 15 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 59)
  - "The International Financial Position of the United Kingdom -- One Year Later", 1954 May 11 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 60)
  - "The Balance of Payments of the Sterling Area in 1954", 1954 December 7 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 61)
  - "Financing of Residential Construction in Western Europe and Canada", 1955 March 15 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 62)
  - "Staff Study of Effects of Credit and Monetary Policy, 1952-54", 1955 April 11 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 63)
  - "Dip or Downturn? The U.K. Balance of Payments in 1954-55", 1955 May 31 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 64)
  - "Comments on U.K. Proposal for Inter-Central Bank Financial Arrangements", 1955 June 27 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 65)
  - "The European Monetary Agreement", 1955 September 6 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 66)
  - "One Year of Inflation: The U.K. Balance of Payments 1954-55", 1955 December 6 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 67)
  - "Indicators of Inflation in Western Europe, 1952-55", 1956 May 1 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 68)
  - "International Relations of the Federal Reserve System", 1958 January 28 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 69)
  - "Recent Proposals to Reform the International Monetary Fund", 1958 March 18 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 70)
  - "Roy Harrod on the Role of Gold Today", 1958 August 19 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 71)
  - "Some Notes on United Nations Economics", 1959 July 21 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 72)
    Also published version.
  - "Recent Developments in International Finance", 1959 November 24 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 73)
  - "Professor Triffin and the Problem of International Monetary Reform", 1961 August 22 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 74)
  - "Problems of the U.S. Balance of International Payments", 1961 December 5 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 75)
  - "John Exeter and the U.S. Balance of Payments", 1962 July 3 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 76)
  - "The U.S. Balance of International Payments", 1962 November 27 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 77)
  - "Comments on the Tobin Proposal to Reform the IMF", 1963 August 27 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 78)
  - "Some Problems of International Payments Reform", 1963 September 17 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 79)
  - "Problems of Reserve Currencies", 1963 October 30 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 80)
  - "Reform of the Reserve Currency System", 1963 December 27 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 81)
  - "The Role of Reserve Currencies in the Payments System", 1964 January 2 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 82)
  - "The 'Dual Basis' of the Payments System and 'Voluntary Abstinence' from Gold Conversion", 1964 January 8 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 83)
  - "Reserve Currencies in the International Payments System", 1964 February 10 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 84)
  - "U.S. Payments Deficit and Domestic Economy", 1964 February 25 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 85)
  - "Balance of Payments and Capital Movements", 1964 May 1 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 86)
  - "The U.S. Balance of Payments -- Present and Future". Speech text, Philadelphia Economists' Discussion Group, 1964 May 19 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 87)
    Published version in Business Review (June 1964), 8-14.
  - "Dr. Holtrop on International Monetary Theory and Policy", 1964 June 4 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 88)
  - "Balance of Payments and Monetary Policy". Federal Reserve Staff Discussion Group, 1964 July 23 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 89)
  - "Results of Discussion of International Liquidity". Committee on Banking and Credit Policy, 1964 July 28 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 90)
  - "The Machlup Report -- A Critical Evaluation", 1964 December 2 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 91)
  - "Problems of Silver Coinage", 1964 December 3 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 92)
  - "Mr. Exeter on the U.S. Payments Deficit -- II", 1965 April 27 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 93)
  - "Problems of Establishing New Types of Reserve Assets", 1965 May 14 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 94)
  - "Official Proposals for International Monetary Reform", 1966 February 3 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 95)
  - "Creation of New Reserve Assets and the U.S. Interest", 1966 February 24 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 96)
  - "Measuring the U.S. Payments Imbalance -- a Restatement", 1966 September 27 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 97)
  - "Examination of the work of the Division", 1966 December 30 (Box 3 (4-Reports and reviews prepared by J. Herbert Furth f), Folder 98)
- Typescripts and published versions of essays, speeches and position papers, 1932-1981; 5; 181 folders
  This series contains typescripts of Furth's numerous lectures and speeches, as well as typescripts of essays written for publication and reviews of works of other economists. Many of the speech texts are revised versions of position papers presented to the Federal Reserve Board. Whenever present in the collection, correspondence related to the lecture is included in the folder, as well as official clearances from the Board.
  - "The Critical Period Before Bankruptcy". Published version in Yale Law Journal, XLI, No. 6 (April 1932), 853-863, Undated (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 1)
  - "Das amerikanische Insolvenzverfahren außerhalb des Konkurses". Published version in Zentralblatt für die Juristische Praxis, No. 5 (1933), 337-380; continued in No. 6, 435-444 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 2)
  - "Juristisches Denken in Amerika". Published version in Oesterreichische Anwalts-Zeitung, X, No. 9 (May 1, 1933), 166-168, Undated (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 3)
  - "Amerikanisches Konkursverfahren". Published version in Zentralblatt für die Juristische Praxis, No. 5, 321-355, 1934 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 4)
  - "Die Reform des Insolvenzwesens im Lichte der amerikanischen Rechtswissenschaft". Published version in Österreichische Richterzeitung, XXVII, No. 1 (January 1934), 4-6, Undated (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 5)
  - "Die wirtschaftlichen Grundlagen des Ausgleichsrechtes". Published version in Juristishe Blätter, LXIV, No. 3 (February 2, 1935), 45-48, Undated (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 6)
  - "Oliver Wendell Holmes †". Published version in Internationales Anwaltsblatt, XXI, No. 2 (April 1935), 49-50, Undated (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 7)
  - "Praktische Aufgaben der Rechtssoziologie". Published version in Zeitschrift für öffentliches Recht, XVII, No. 3, 273-286, 1936 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 8)
  - "A Note on Pure Competition", ca. 1939; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 9)
  - "Economics of Price Cutting", 1939 April 8; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 10)
  - "The Development of Nazism in Central Europe", ca. 1940; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 11)
  - "Maintenance of Recovery in Totalitarian States", ca. 1940; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 12)
  - "Misconceptions of National Socialism". Text of speech, Lyons' Club, Oxford, PA, 1940 February 2 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 13)
  - Untitled speech text, Rotary Club, Oxford, PA, 1940 March 11 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 14)
  - Untitled speech text, Farmers' Club, 1940 March 23 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 15)
  - "The American Gold Problem", 1940 October 31; typescript (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 16)
  - Untitled speech text, Rotary Club Kennet Square, 1940 December 26 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 17)
  - "The United States and Europe". Newspaper clipping from The Lincolnian, 1941 November 27 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 18)
  - "Earnings and Employment in the Business Cycle". Published version in The Review of Economic Statistics, XXIV, No. 3 (August 1942), 136-142, Undated (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 19)
  - "The Case for Trade Unions". Speech text, Oxford Rotary Club, 1942 November 30 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 20)
  - "Chapel Talk", Lincoln University, 1944 November 7 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 21)
  - "Breton Woods Agreement". Speech text, Oxford Rotary, 1944 November 7 (Box 4 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 22)